



Krishna KR Krishna KR (1) Featured | [7] Senior Consultant seeking roles in Program Management, Business Analysis, Digital Consulting, Product Management, Vendor Management, Scrum Framework, Client Engagement, web application, Service Delivery, Magento, SAP Lumira, Jira, Hotjar Current Designation: Senior Consultant - Cognizant Digital Total Experience: 16 Year(s) 0 Month(s) Business Notice Period: 2 Months Current Company: Cognizant Consulting Highest Degree: Master of Science [Information Current Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore Technology and Management] Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore. Chennai. Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming / Maintenance Role: Outside Consultant Industry: Strategy/Management Consulting Firms Marital Status: Married

Last Active: 20-Jan-21 Last Modified: 20-Jan-21

Jump to Section Work Exp

SAP Lumira, Jira, Hotjar

Verified: Phone Number

Work Experience | Education | IT Skills |

Key Skills: Senior Consultant, Program Management, Business Analysis, Digital Consulting, Product

-Management, Vendor Management, Scrum-Framework, Client Engagement, web application, Service Delivery, Magento,

#### Summary

A value creating professional with over 16 years of IT experience in Business - Digital Consulting and Management space. Engaged in various assignments relating to Customer experience, Go-to market, Sales improvement, Cost reduction, New feature launch and Setting up digital operation. Currently working for a North American beverages giant in improving the customer experience for its e-commerce business. Set up e-commerce operations and helped Chinese telecom leader to improve the sales in KSA and UAE by planning and executing campaigns with an end to end responsibility. Drove a 'Digital Transformation' assignment involving 3rd party vendors for a mobile app and a web application targeted to enhance briefing experience for the visiting clients.

Based on the solid foundation of impeccable experience, steered senior leadership roles as the knowledge has always been pioneering operations from the ground level. Took ownership and accountability of KPIs and success measures

### **Work Experience**

Cognizant Consulting as Senior Consultant - Cognizant Digital Business Jan 2016 to Till Date

E-Commerce: Customer Experience / Product Owner for Nestle Water's Readyrefresh, NA

\* Currently helping Readyrefresh.com in achieving its '2020 Vision' by launching a new service and new features to enhance the customer experience, which includes dashboards and subscription model.

Engage product and user experience teams to understand customer demand for new features

Document product and service order workflows and processes

Create valuable user stories with a clear acceptance criterion to get buy-in from stakeholders

Responsible for creating, maintaining and prioritizing the product backlog

Facilitate the sprint and iteration planning to give a better understanding of the functionalities to the scrum team

Participate in estimation sessions and slice down stories as required to accommodate in the sprints

Drove A/B testing effort to decide on the variant to improve add to cart and subsequent conversion to sale (ECR) Defined 'Engagement Metrics' to measure the new service performance and to focus on the improvement area

E-Commerce: Event Management / Agile Program Manager cum Product Owner for Huawei ME, IND & US

- \* Middle East e-Shop Operations:
- o Launched UAE and KSA Huawei operations with 2 sites each for English and Arabic in 'Lean Startup' model
- Planned and executed more than 40 campaigns, by consistently improving the user experience Engaged with cross-functional teams such as Visual Design, UX/UI, CS, Traffic and Legal

Increased the traffic by 4X, registrations by 3X and orders by 2X Implemented bundle strategy by recommending products through market basket analysis

Product Management: Ideated and implemented Registration Page, Loyalty Page, Omni-channel - 'Shop online-Pickup Offline' and B2B Sales.

\* India Rush-Buy Program:

Introduced 'Rush-buy' system in India for 'Honor' mobiles, which was primarily designed in 'Chinese' Planned and executed more than 35 'Rush-buys' for India to increase registrations and attract traffic Contributed about 40% of overall registration for the year 2018, which was considered to be a key KPI Conducted the 'Rush-buy' sale in exclusive Mobile App channel for the first time

# **Important**

 Using Free CV Search you have access to featured candidate profiles of Naukri. You can browse through the profiles and email the candidates of your choice directly using the email option provided. To prevent misuse of candidate information, contact details and attached resume of the candidates have been withheld CONTRACTOR BY THE STATE OF THE

Acquired a new account at \$0.32 cents which is 20% less against the standard cost \$0.40 cents Product Management: Automated the system by introducing the configuration elements to make it simpler and effective

Digital Transformation: Client Briefing Experience / Product Owner

- \* Complete re-imagination of client visits which is considered to be highly strategic
- \* Defined success criteria built around functionality, technology, performance and integration
- \* Evaluated a mobile app to engross the visiting clients for a growth enriched relationship and a back-end web application for a detailed planning by the teams
- \* Engaged with 'Idea Couture' a 'design thinking' firm to arrive at arrived at a 'Customer Journey Map'
- \* Involved cross functional stakeholders such as IT, Business, Legal, Info Security, Privacy and Leadership to build a consensus

#### Engagement Model Transformation: Pricing Model / Product Owner

- \* Played an imperative role as a Product Owner in the implementation of Vested Model Pricing (VMP)
- \* Documented product workflows, processes and business architecture diagram to clearly depict the impacted areas
- \* Created product backlog with the value driven user stories
- \* Participated in estimation sessions and slice down stories as required to accommodate in the sprints
- \* Conducted 'Product Market Fit' to take the optimal features to the target audience
- \* Defined the execution plan through 8 sprints, by achieving the MP in 4 sprints

Complex Program Management: Program Rescue / Program Manager

\* Played a Customer Focussed vital role in recovering the off-track program called iPlus for Toyota North America, aimed at enhancing its incentive system for its dealers) by re-planning efforts and rolling-out various operational strategies

## Verizon Data Services India as Consultant -Program Management

Nov 2010 to Jan 2016

#### As PMO Manager

- \* Worked on the Verizon Rapid Delivery program, managing domain provisioning, which involves taking the product to customers (the domain included 15 applications, and delivered approximately 40 projects for release)
- \* Ensured project alignment towards organizational goals and business case/initiatives in collaboration with portfolio management/project managers; segregated projects by T-Shirt size and bucketed as per complexity
- \* Implemented rigorous risk management methodologies for key complex projects as well as created weekly dashboard to report individual release health to executives through bucketing projects as Red/Amber/Green
- \* Tracked projects going through Change Control Board for adding/changing requirements to programs
- \* Introduced PM Quality Index to measure the performance of IT PMs who drove projects across multiple releases
- \* Managed stakeholder expectations and drove project managers to provide quality project deliverables to publish

#### As Transformation Program Manager

- \* Looked after the program known as" Verizon Rapid Delivery" for enterprise products offered, in a bid to reduce sales cycle by 70% from the initial opportunity identification stage till billing; processes involved opportunity identification, quote configuration, pricing, quote completion, contract signing, operation, provisioning, billing and CRM
- \* Participated in Portfolio Management reviews to check impacted systems contain enough budget/capacity to execute project for every other release during Project Prioritization phase
- \* Discussed around HLAs, BREQs, SREQs and LOE during Project Commitment phase and arrived at business benefits
- \* Performed sign-off during development phase for Release Level Detail Design from architecture team and a runthrough to be done with Dev, QA, and Architecture POCs

## As Project Manager

- \* Owned an end to end program roll out to improve go-to market of third-party widgets on FiOS platform partnering with HCL (Vendor), thereby trained teams, inspected and certified lab for operation, monitored performance and stabilized the complete engagement by involving crucial stakeholders
- \* Effectively handled the 'Change' by addressing cultural aspect of both the Organisations
- Collaborated with global PMO team to acquire access for project execution and fine-tuned processes which includes curbing of 12 hours' delay in code drop and managed stakeholder expectation

#### CSS Corp as Senior Business Analyst

Jul 2007 to Oct 2010

- \* Played a pivotal role in managing projects and led a team of BAs with respect to Project Management and Process Compliance for one of a key account
- \* Provided high-end support on portal developments in Educational and Accounts Receivable Module for Legal Domain
- \* Instrumental in streamlining Business Analysis Process by investigating & understanding key business issues and providing clear recommendations as well as introducing new techniques
- \* Handled consultations to arrive at 'Make or Buy' decision and attained proficiency in change management process

^ Back to Top

## Education

UG: B.Com (Commerce) from Madurai Kamaraj University (MKU) in 1997

PG: Master of Science (Information Technology and Management) from Madurai Kamaraj University (MKU) in 1999

Other Qualifications/Certifications/Programs:
Project Management Professional (PMP)
Professional Scrum Product Owner (PSPO) 1
Leadership Through Design Innovation
Digital Product Management: Modern Fundamentals

^ Back to Top

## IT Skills

Skill Name Version Last Used Experience

INDETOJEG	
MS Excel, MS Visio	
MINITAB	
BizAgi Process Modeller	
Freemind, Agro UML	
SAP Lumira and SAP Xcelsius	
Jira, Hotjar	

^ Back to Top

# Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak	
English	Expert	✓	✓	✓	
Tamil	Expert	✓	✓	✓	

^ Back to Top

# **Affirmative Action**

# **Work Authorization**

Category: **General**Physically Challenged: **No** 

Job Type: Permanent
Employment Status: Full time

^ Back to Top

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.

Careers - About Us - Clients - Terms & Conditions - FAQ's - Contact Us - Report a Problem - Site Map - Resources
Our Partners: Jeevansathi Matrimonials - ICIClcommunities.org - 99acres - Real Estate In India
All rights reserved © 2021 Info Edge India Ltd.